### ADITYA KULKARNI

645 Newark Avenue, Jersey City 07306 | +1 551-328-8653. | <u>kulkarniaditya1002@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u>

#### **PROFILE**

Skilled and results-oriented professional with a solid academic and professional experience in software engineering, product development, data engineering, machine learning, working in Agile environment, DevOps, requirement analysis, and with a key achievement: Certificate of appreciation by client for dedication and valuable contribution towards project success. My strengths include leadership, adaptability, public speaking, problem solving.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, USA

**September 2022 - Present** 

Graduate student in MS(Data science, Fall 2022)

# MIT-World Peace University, Pune, India

April-2020

Secured a Master's degree in Big Data Analytics with *Distinction* (8.35/10.0)

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: R(Intermediate), Python(Proficient), Javascript(Intermediate).
- **Platforms**: Databricks(Notebooks), AWS (EC2, Lambda, Glue, Sagemaker, ALB), Azure(Data Factory, Blob storage, VM).
- **OS**: Suse, Ubuntu, Windows.
- Software/Tools: Docker, Git, Apache Airflow.
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Snowflake.
- Web framework : Django, Node.js, Serverless framework.
- **Technologies/Modules**: SQL, NLTK, Pandas, Spark, Keras, Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Object oriented programming(OOP), REST framework.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Inteliment Technologies, Pune, India

**July 2021 – April 2022** 

### Software Engineer – Product development.

- Worked as a Data Engineer to develop profitability matrix in python for Asia's largest bike manufacturing client
- Worked as Data Engineer for an AI powered digital marketing application client, performed ETL operations in AWS Glue and Databricks, worked on Serverless applications using python and nodeJS, deployed the application on AWS Lambda.

#### Associate Software Engineer

**September 2020 – June 2021** 

- Worked as DevOps engineer, carrying out application deployments and managing customer's cloud and local environments.
- Worked as a co-architect for designing an IoT data flow framework, did a groundwork on protocols like MQTT, WSS and developing proof of concept IoT solution for analysis of vibration sensor.

# Project Trainee - Intern

November 2019 – September 2020

- Worked as R&D engineer, developing proof of concept documents that demonstrated the working of time series algorithms and delivered the KT to product developers.
- Functioned as a co-developer for a sentiment analysis project, input data was from Google customer reviews about the product and how were the services offered by the respective dealer of that product.

### **PROJECTS**

# **Image search application** | *Python, Angular.js, deep learning*.

Ongoing

2021-2022

• Implementing (Vanilla, Convolutional, VGG19) autoencoder and will evaluate the performance by using high quality, noisy and gray scale image data. Evaluation of the model will be based on SSIM, MSE metric.

### Data engineering for Social Media Marketing Application | Python, spark, node.js, AWS.

- Developed ETL scripts in AWS Glue and databricks notebooks for ETL operations.
- Developed Serverless applications with AWS Lambda and reduced the data collection time from 15 minutes to 8 minutes.
- Updated a retrieval logic by improving data retrieval query execution time from 8 minutes to 3 minutes, which was required for providing recommendations on the application side.

# **Sentiment Analysis - Customer Reviews** | *Python, Django, machine learning.*

2020-2021

- Developed an API in Django to get the customer reviews from the client portal, to automate data collection.
- Pre-processed the data using NLTK library, got 90% accuracy with XGBoost for sentiment classification.